

Curriculum Vitae for Sebastian Franco Ulloa

Personal information

Address: Helgesens gate 14D E-mail: sebastian.ulloa@xal.no

0553 Oslo Phone: +47 466 79 133

Born: 28.07.1993

Summary

Consultant at Expert Analytics AS. PhD in biotechnological sciences with a background in physics and chemistry. My areas of interest include data science (analysis and visualization), machine learning, drug discovery, nanomaterials, and the theory of evolution. My values are based on the scientific method, critical thinking, and teaching. I am an analytical and compassionate person prompt to hear different perspectives on the same problem, to consolidate them into the most informed and reasonable judgement possible.

Technical skills

Applications Supervised machine learning, Molecular dynamics, Mathe

deling, Data visualization, Finite element methods, Design of experi-

ments, Scientific writing

Languages Python, C, SQL, bash

Packages Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Pandas, Matplotlib, Bokeh, Tkinter, Se-

aborn, Numpy

Tools Ipython, GitHub, Linux, VMD, Gromacs, Microsoft Office Suite

Education

2017 - 2021	PhD Biotechnological sciences. Italian Institute of Technology. Ge-
	noa, Italy
2017 - 2020	Data science certificates of accomplishment. DataCamp, Inc. On-
	line
2020	Leading Digital Transformation online course (6 weeks). Mas-
	sachusetts Institute of Technology - Professional Education. Online
2012 - 2017	BSc. Physics. University of Los Andes. Bogota, Colombia
2011 - 2016	BSc. Chemistry. University of Los Andes. Bogota, Colombia
2016 - 2019	Modern Physics at All Scales summer school. University of Leiden.
	Leiden, The Netherlands

Professional experience

2021 - Present	Consultant. Expert Analytics. Oslo, Norway
2018 - 2021	Research collaborator. Italian Institute of Technology. Genoa, Italy
2019	Guest researcher (6 months). Hylleraas Centre for Quantum Mole-
	cular Sciences. Oslo, Norway
2016	Part-time professor (6 months). University of Los Andes. Bogota,
	Colombia
2015 - 2017	Teaching assistant. University of Los Andes. Bogota, Colombia
2016	Accompaniment program tutor. University of Los Andes. Bogota,
	Colombia

Languages

English Highly proficient in speaking and writing

Italian Proficient in speaking and intermediate writing skills

Spanish Native

Personal skills

Data Intrinsically motivated to creating visually appealing representations

visualization of data

Problem Interested in merging seemingly disconnected concepts into innovative

solving and creative perspectives

Statistics Solid background in statistics resulting from a training in scientific

research

Teaching Passionate about sharing knowledge both in formal and informal set-

tings

Some interests and hobbies

Leisure Music, knitting, pet-sitting

Miscellaneous Generative art, the Theory of Evolution, jewel crafting

Physical Boxing, dancing, acrobatics, yoga, hiking

activity